[[{"question":"The date of commencement of the Indian Constitution is","choices":["26-11-1949","26-11-1945","26-01-1950","15-08-1947"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Preamble of Indian Constitution indicates","choices":["Privigileges given to SC & ST","The power of government to make laws","The circumstances under which the Constitution can be amended","The source of the Indian Constitution"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"The source of authority of the Indian Constitution is","choices":["The Government","The people of India","The Supreme Court","The President"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"One of the objective of the Constitution is to achieve","choices":["Law and order","Justice","Political Stability","Social Control"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The word secular as used in the preamble indicates","choices":["Treating all the languages equally","Special treatment to Hindu religion","Treating all the religions equally","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The state whose executive head is elected representative is called","choices":["The Republic","Anarchy","Monarchy","Dictatorship"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The first written document with respect to basic rights is the","choices":["Magna Carta of England","Constitution of India","Constitution of America","French declaration of rights of man and citizen"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Fundamental Rights are protected by the","choices":["Civil Courts","Criminal Court","Supreme Court","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Fundamental Rights are","choices":["Civil Rights","Criminal Rights","Basic Rights","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Part-3 of the Constitution guarantees how many categories of Fundamental Rights","choices":["Five","Six","Seven","Eight"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The right to equality means","choices":["Treating all citizens equally","Treating government servant equally","Treating citizens differently","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Equality must be among","choices":["Equals","In-equal","All","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Article 14 permits reasonable","choices":["Classification","Discriminations","Division","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"State is prohibited from denying any citizens access to","choices":["Shops, Public Restaurants etc.","private places","Men & Women","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"State is authorized to make special provision for","choices":["Women & Children","Men only","Men & Women ","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"State can make special provisions for the advancement of","choices":["Socially and economically backward classes of citizens","Economically backward classes of citizens","Only socially backward classes of citizens","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Equality in public employment means","choices":["All applicants are entitled to be employed","State has to give equal opportunity in public employment without discrimination","State cannot prescribe any condition of employment","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"...........can be the ground for reservation of posts","choices":["Language","Residence ","Colour of the person","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Untouchability is","choices":["An offence","Not an offence","Permissible","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The Constitution provides for the abolition of","choices":["Titles","Salaries of public servants","Allowances of the members of the parliament","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The freedom of speech includes","choices":["Freedom of press","Freedom of disturbing public peace","Freedom to create nuisance","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Freedom of speech and expression means right to express one's own opinion only by","choices":["Words by mouth","Writing and printing","Both as mentioned above","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Freedom of speech includes","choices":["Freedom of silence","Freedom of insulting others","Both as mentioned above","None of these "],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Classification of films into 'A' & 'U' is","choices":["Valid","Invalid","Either of the mentioned above","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Freedom of assembly means right to assemble peacefully","choices":["With arms","Without arms","With deadly weapons","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Freedom of association includes","choices":["Freedom to move","Freedom to form companies","Freedom to reside & settle","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The freedom of movement under Article 19 (1) (d) can be restricted in the interest of","choices":["Women","Law & Order","General public","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Freedom of Residence means right to","choices":["Reside and settle only in a particular area","Reside and settle in any part of the territory of India","Reside in a foreign country","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Right to Property is a","choices":["Ordinary Right","Fundamental Right","Moral Right","Not a Right"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The Constitution guarantees Right to Practice","choices":["any profession, occupation, trade or business","Only profession","Both as mentioned above","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The Constitution guarantees  Fundamental rights to","choices":["Both citizens and Non-citizens","Citizens only","Foreigners only","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Ex-post facto law means","choices":["Law imposing penalties from a previous date","Law imposing penalties from a future date","Civil Law","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Double Jeopardy means","choices":["No prosecution and punishment for the same offence more than once","There can be prosecution and punishment for the same offence more than once","Double benefit","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Self-incrimination means","choices":["Compulsion to be a witness against himself","Compulsion to be a witness against others","Voluntarily gives evidence","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Article 21 protects","choices":["Life only","Liberty only","Life & Personal Liberty","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Right to life includes","choices":["Right to live with human dignity","Right to not live with human dignity","Right to mere animal existence","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Right to Shelter is part of","choices":["Right to live","Right to equality","Right to freedom","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"An arrested person has ____ number of rights under Article 22","choices":["4","5","1","6"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The first right under Article 22 is","choices":["Right to be informed of grounds of arrest","Right to consult his own lawyer","Right to be produced before a magistrate","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"An arrested person must be produced before a magistrate within ___ hours of his arrest","choices":["12","24","36","48"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Telephone tapping is violation of","choices":["Right to Freedom of Speech & Expression","Right to life and personal liberty","Right to carry on any profession","Right to equality"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"A person can be detained under Preventive Detention Law","choices":["If he has committed offences against the public","If he is likely to cause harm to public","If he is insolvent","If he is alien enemy"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Right to pollution free environment includes","choices":["Right to life","Freedom of Speech and Expression","Right to religion","Abolition of Untouchability"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Right to life includes","choices":["Prisoners Rights","Teachers Right","Students Rights","Ministers Rights"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Right to Education is a","choices":["Fundamental Rights","Ordinary legal Right","Not a Right","Both as mentioned above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Traffic in human beings & labour is","choices":["Prohibited under the Constitution","Permitted under the Constitution","Both as mentioned above","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Children below the age of ___ years are prohibited to be employed in hazardous employment","choices":["21 years","18 years","14 years","30 years"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Right to Freedom of Religion aims at achieving the concept of","choices":["Secularism","Federalism","Political justice","Economic justice"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"There can be prohibition of religious instruction is _____ institutions","choices":["State aided","Unaided","Minority Educational","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The tax collected by the state cannot be utilized","choices":["For the promotion of any particular religion","For the promotion of any particular business","Both as mentioned above","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Cultural and Educational Rights are also known as","choices":["Minority Rights","Majority Rights","Both as mentioned above","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Minorities have Right to","choices":["Establish and administer Educational institutions","Only to establish educational institutions","Carry on profession or business","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Minorities under Article 30 are based on","choices":["Religion or language","Religion only","Language only","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"___is the custodian of Fundamental Rights","choices":["Supreme Court & High Court","Civil Courts","President of India","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The Supreme Court is situated at","choices":["New Delhi","Mumbai","Bangalore","Kolkata"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The founding father of the Indian Constitution is","choices":["Dr.B.R.Ambekar","Gandhiji","Pandit Nehru","Sardar Valabhai Patel"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Supreme Court has power to issue _____ Kinds of writs","choices":["3","4","5","6"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Habeas Corpus means","choices":["You may have the body","What is your authority","Arrest the person","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Who can apply for Habeas Corpus Writ?","choices":["The person arrested only","Any friend/relative of an arrested person","The police officer","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Mandamus means","choices":["Command","Request","Permission","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Mandamus writ lies against","choices":["Public authority","Private persons","Both as mentioned above","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Writ of Prohibition is issued against","choices":["Inferior Court","Tribunal","Both as mentioned above","Superior court"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Certiorari  means","choices":["To certify","To produce a person illegally arrested","Command","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"'Quo-Warranto' means","choices":["What is your authority","Direction","Issuina warrant","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"'Locus Standi' means","choices":["Right to move the Supreme Court/High Court","Right to be defended","Local authority","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Supreme Court has invented a new doctrine called","choices":["Public Interest Litigation","Private Interest Litigation","Publicity Interest Litigation","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Right to Education is contained in Article","choices":["Article 20","Article 21","Article 21A","Article 32"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Right to property is a","choices":["Fundamental Right","Legal Right","Mortal Right","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Right to start a business under Article 19 (1)(g) includes","choices":["Right not to close down the business","Right to close down the business","Right to travel abroad","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The number of Articles in the Constitution presently is","choices":["368","395","400","447"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Directive Principles of State Policy are contained in which part of the Constitution?","choices":["Part I","Part III","Part IV","Part-II"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The underlying objective of the Directive Principles is to achieve","choices":["Welfare State","police State","Secular State","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"There is right to adequate means of livelihood guaranteed to","choices":["Both men & women equally","men only","Women only","either men or to women"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"'Equal Pay for Equal Work' is an accompaniment of","choices":["Right to freedom","Right to equality","Right to freedom of religion","Right to constitutional remedies"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The Directive Principles of State Policy","choices":["Can be enforced in any court","Cab be enforced in High Court","Cannot be enforced in any Court","can be enforced only in the Supreme Court"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The Directive Principles of State Policy to be followed by the State for securing economic justice does not include","choices":["equal pay for equal work","to secure uniform civil code","equal right of men & women to adequate means of livelihood","to protect health & strength of workers"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Sexual harassment of working women is violation of","choices":["Fundamental duty","Fundamental right","Directive Principles of State Policy","Rule of law"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"This Act was not passed for implementing Directive Principles of State Policy","choices":["Forest Act","Maternity Benefit Act","Water Pollution Act","Arms Act"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Directive Principles of State Policy are","choices":["Political rights","Social rights","Constitutional rights","Legal rights"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"This is not a Directive Principle of State Policy","choices":["Living wage for workers","Right to work, education","Secure just & corrupt free judiciary","Participation of workers in management of Industries"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Uniform Civil Code means","choices":["Uniform Civil Procedure Code","Civil law applicable to common man","Common civil law applicable to all","Civil law applicable to Hindu Women & Muslim Women"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Free & Compulsory education for all children is provided under Article 45 until they attain the age of","choices":["14 years","21 years","18 years","16 years"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Equal justice & free aid is guaranteed to","choices":["Socially backward classes","Economically backward classes","Socially & economically backward classes","Educationally backward classes"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"State should protect every monument or place or object declared to be of","choices":["State importance","National importance","International importance","Local importance"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"State should take steps to separate","choices":["Judiciary from Executive","Legislature from Executive","Judiciary from Legislature","All the 3 organs from each other"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The object of organizing Village Panchayats is to introduce","choices":["Democracy at grass-root level","Indirect democracy","Aristocracy","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Fundamental Rights and Directive Principles are","choices":["unrelated to each other","Supplementary & Complementary","Opposed to each other","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Part-IV (A) consists of ____ fundamental duties","choices":["10","9","11","12"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Part-IV (A) was added to the Constitution in the year","choices":["1950","1972","1978","1976"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"For the violation of fundamental duties, an action","choices":["can be initiated in any court","can be initiated in the magistrate court","cannot be initiated in any court","can be initiated either in High Court or in Supreme court"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The Remedy available for breach of Fundamental Duties under the Constitution is","choices":["filing civil suit","filing criminal complaint","no remedy","filing Writ Petition"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Fundamental Duty demands","choices":["To work sincerely & respect the right of others","To abide by the Constitution","To prevent corruption","To abide by ethical values"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Which of the following is not a fundamental duty","choices":["to protect & improve natural environment","not to practice corruption","to develop scientific temper","to abide by Constitution"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The recent fundamental duty is","choices":["Duty of a parent or guardian to provide education to his child","Duty to safeguard public property","Duty to protect & improve the natural environment","Duty to abide by the Constitution"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Fundamental duties in the Constitution are addressed to the","choices":["Politicians","People","Workers","Students"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The Directive Principles of State Policy are in the form of","choices":["Rights","duties","Direction to state","obligation citizens"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The Constitution makers have borrowed the Directive Principles from","choices":["Constitution of Spain","Constitution of U.K.","Constitution of U.S.A","Constitution of Ireland"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"The Directive Principles of State Policy are the obligations of","choices":["Central Govt.","State Govt.","Central & State Govt.","Citizen of India"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Article 37 of the constitution declares that the Directive Principles are","choices":["Enforceable in a court of law","Unenforceable","Enforceable only","None of them"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Article 38 of the Constitution aims to achieve","choices":["Social Justice","Economic Justice","Political Justice","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The State is required to direct its policy towards securing equal right to a adequate means of livelihood for","choices":["Disabled persons","Men only","Women","Both men and Women"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"In Child Labour Abolition case the Supreme Court has held that the children below the age of ____ cannot be employed in any hazardous industry","choices":["16 years","18 years","21 years","14 years"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"The Parliament of India has enacted ___ for the enforcement of Article 39(d)","choices":["Child labour Abolition Act","Equal remuneration Act","Protect of Human Rights Act","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Equal justice and free legal aid under the Social Security Charter has to be provided to","choices":["Socially backward classes","Economically backward classes","Politically backward","All of the above"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Now, free legal aid and speedy trial are","choices":["Only directives","Duty of the citizens","Fundamental rights","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"State has been directed to provide employment, education & public assistance in cases of unemployment for the unemployed, aged, sick and disabled","choices":["Irrespective of economic capacity of the nation","Out of the borrowings","Out of Consolidated Fund","Within the economic capacity of the state"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Living wage means","choices":["Minimum wage","Bare necessitates of life","Provision for education and insurance","Education & insurance etc. including the necessities of life"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Provision for care & education to children has been inserted as a Fundamental Right under","choices":["Article 21","Article 20","Article 21(A)","Article 31(A)"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Education below the age of 14 years is inserted as a fundamental right by","choices":["42nd Amendment","44th Amendment","85th Amendment","86th Amendment"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"The Directive Principles under Article 46 considered ___ as educationally & economically backward/weaker sections of the society","choices":["Women & children","Disabled","SCs and STs","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"To protect and improve the natural environment and wild life is one of","choices":["Fundamental Rights","National policy","Directive Principles","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Article 48 of the Constitution directs the state to take steps to organize","choices":["Agriculture sector","Animal husbandry","both as mentioned above ","Scientific and technological advancement"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Monuments and places and objects of national importance are protected because India is a country with","choices":["Richest population","Lengthiest Constitution","Rich cultural heritage","Diverse culture"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The Directive Principle in Art.53 for promotion of international peace and Security became justifiable by","choices":["Universal Declaration of Human Rights, 1948","Protection of Human Rights Act, 1993","The Equal Remuneration Act 1976","All of the mentioned above"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Democracy at the grass root level is strengthened by","choices":["Municipalities","State legislatures","Village panchayats","Central government"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The fundamental rights and directive principles are","choices":["conflicting with each other","unrelated to each other","complement & supplement to each other","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Who is known as the first citizen of India?","choices":["The President","Prime Minister","Speaker","Chief Election Commissioner"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Who is the Head of the State?","choices":["Governor","Prime Minister","President","Vice-President"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Who is the Head of the Executive?","choices":["A Cabinet","Cabinet headed by the Prime Minister","President","Speaker"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Who is the Nominal Head of the Executive?","choices":["A Prime Minister","Vice-President","President","Governor"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"How much age is required by a person, to contest in the Presidential Election?","choices":["30+","32+","33+","35+"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Name the group, which is created for the election of the President?","choices":["Electoral College","Elected College","Electoral Commission","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Who are the members of the Electoral College?","choices":["Elected members of both Houses of Parliament & elected MLA's","Almost all members of Parliament","Members of Parliament of Lok Sabha","Members of Parliament of Rajya Sabha"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What kind of system of voting followed in President's election?","choices":["A open ballot system","Voting by oral announcement","Secret ballot system","Partial ballot system"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Who has to take an oath of the Person who won in the President's election?","choices":["Outgoing President","Chief Justice of India","Prime Minister","Governor"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What is the term of the office of the president?","choices":["4 years","5 years","6 years","2 years"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What is the maximum period for election of the President, if Vacancy is raised due to the death, resignation or removal of the President?","choices":["within 1 year","within 1 and a half years","within 6 months","within 2 months"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Name the bill or motion aimed to remove the President?","choices":["Impeachment Motion","no-confidence motion","Judgment of the Supreme Court","Majority approval of the Parliament"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Who is the authorized person to remove the President after the Impeach Motion is passed in Parliament?","choices":["Chief Justice of India","Vice-President","Prime Minister","Parliament"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Who can be appointed by the President as the P.M.?","choices":["Leader of the majority party in the Rajya Sabha","Leader of the party in the Lok Sabha","Leader of the majority party in LokaSabha","Leader of the opposition party in the Rajya Sabha"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"How does the appointment of Council of Ministers take place?","choices":["Appointed by the Prime Minister","By the President","By the President on the advice of the P.M","By the P.M on the advice of the President"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Who is the Supreme Commander of the defence forces of India?","choices":["Prime Minister","Parliament","Chief Justice of S.C.","The President"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Who Can control or regulate the exercise of military powers of the President?","choices":["Constitution","Parliament","Prime Minister","President"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Is the President a part of the Parliament?","choices":["No","Yes","Upto 3 years of the term","Upto 1 year of the term"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Who can dissolve the Lok Sabha?","choices":["The President","Prime Minister","Supreme Court","Speaker of Lok Sabha"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Can the President withhold an Ordinary Bill?","choices":["No","Yes","Can withhold upto 6 months","upto 1 year"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What is the total strength of the Rajya Sabha?","choices":["50","225","250","238"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"What is the life of the ordinance from the date of commencement of the sessions of the Parliament?","choices":["one year","nine months","six months","six weeks"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Who has the power to declare emergency?","choices":["Parliament","President","Prime Minister","Supreme Court"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Which Article empowers the President to impose National Emergency?","choices":["356","360","352","359"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Which Article empowers the President to impose State Emergency?","choices":["356","357","358","359"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which Article empowers the President to impose Financial Emergency?","choices":["361","362","363","360"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"At what occasion President can impose National Emergency?","choices":["During internal rebellion","War","War & armed rebellion","During constitutional crisis"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"At what occasion the President can impose a State Emergency?","choices":["Failure of the State Government to rule as per the Constitution","Failure of the state Government to rule as per the Supreme Court","Failure of the state Government to rule as per the High Court","Failure of the state Government to rule as per the Governor"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Who can become the Prime Minister?","choices":["Leader of the opposition party is Lok Sabha","The leader of the majority political party in the Lok Sabha","Leader of the Ruling Party","Leaders of both houses"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Can the President appoint other ministers without the advice of the PM?","choices":["No","Only the ministers can be appointed","Yes","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What is the main hurdle to be crossed by the ruling party after being invited by the President to form the Government?","choices":["Cabinet should prove their majority in the Lok Sabha within the stipulated time given by the President","Should prove majority in the Rajya Sabha","Should prove the Majority in S.C.","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Can the PM advise the President to appoint a non-MP as a Minister?","choices":["No","Advise the speaker","Advise the Parliament","Yes"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"For how much period a non-MP can be allowed as minister?","choices":["3 months","Six months","9 Months","12 months"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What condition has to be fulfilled if a non-MP to continue as a minister?","choices":["He has to elect as a member of Parliament within six months failing which he has to resign his post","to become MP in 3 months","within one year","no time limit"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Can a non-MP be continued as a minister without being elected?","choices":["No such rule","No","Yes","None"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Who can allot and transfer the portfolios to the ministers?","choices":["The Prime Minister","The President","Parliament","Cabinet"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Who is the authorized person to remove the ministers at anytime?","choices":["Advising the speaker","By advising the vice-president","Prime Minister by advising the president","By advising cabinet"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Who can supervise and control the business of the administration?","choices":["The Prime Minister","Cabinet","President","Supreme Court"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Who can conduct and postpone the cabinet meetings?","choices":["Speaker","Parliament","The President","The PM"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Union Legislature of India is know as","choices":["Electoral body","The Parliament","Diet","Congress"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"How many Houses are there in parliament?","choices":["Five","Two","Three","Four"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Which Houses of Parliament represents Federal features?","choices":["Rajya Sabha","Lok Sabha","Vidhana Sabha","Vidhana Parishad"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What kind of elections takes place to Rajya Sabha?","choices":["Direct elections","Indirect election","by-elections","mid-term election"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"If people's representatives, participate in the elections it is known as","choices":["Direct elections","Indirect elections","by-election","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"How many parts does the Parliament consists? What are those?","choices":["Two parts Lok Sabha and Rajya Sabha","4 parts Lok Sabha, Rajya Sabha, Speaker & President","One members of Parliament","Three- Lok Sabha, Rajya Sabha, and the President"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Which is the powerful House of Parliament?","choices":["Rajya Sabha","Lok Sabha","President","Prime Minister"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Is the President an integral part of Parliament?","choices":["Yes","No","to some extent Yes","to some extent No"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"How does the Lok Sabha form?","choices":["Indirect","On the basis of the direct elections","No elections","Nomination"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"How many MPs to Lok Sabha are elected directly by the States of the nation?","choices":["545","540","525","500"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"How many members from the Union Territories are elected to the Lok Sabha?","choices":["50","30","25","20"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"What is the maximum strength of the Lok Sabha?","choices":["552","425","545","560"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What is the term of the Lok Sabha?","choices":["2 years","6 years","4 years","5 years"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"When does the normal time of Lok Sabha extend?","choices":["Civil war","War","During the emergency","floods"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Name the elections take place for the whole Lok Sabha before its expiry?","choices":["Indirect elections","Mid-term elections","General elections","Bi-elections"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Name the elections take place for a few vacancies of Lok Sabha before the expiry of the term?","choices":["Direct","Indirect elections","None of these","Bi-elections"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"For how much period the term of Lok Sabha can be extended during emergency?","choices":["One year","Six months","Two years","Three years"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Within which time the elections should be conducted to the Lok Sabha after the Emergency is ceased to operate?","choices":["12 months","within 6 months","3 months","9 months"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Is there any educational qualification for becoming MP?","choices":["some qualification","yes","No","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"For how much period mid term election are conducted?","choices":["5 years","3 years","4 years","2 years"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The required age to contest in the election of the Lok Sabha is","choices":["Below 25 years","30 years","25 years+","35 year"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Who is the Presiding officer of the Lower House of Parliament?","choices":["Vice-president","Speaker","Prime Minister","President"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Can the Speaker continue in his post after loosing membership in the House?","choices":["Yes after SC permission","No","Yes","don't know"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Who will elect the Speaker of the Lower House?","choices":["President","Members of the Lower House","Prime Minister","Vice-president"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Who will act as Speaker in his absence?","choices":["Vice-President","Defence Minister","Home Minister","Deputy Speaker"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"How is the Speaker removed?","choices":["by the President","By the Prime Minister","By the Parliament","When the Lower House passes a resolution by an absolute majority after a notice is issued 14 days in advance for such removal before passing of resolution by the President"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"If any member elected as a Speaker, can be continue in his political party?","choices":["yes","By the permission of the SC, he can continue","None of these","No, He should resign his political party"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"How many kinds of Bill are there?","choices":["Three kinds","One kind","Two kinds","five kinds"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"If the Bill is introduced by opposition and independent MP, it is known as","choices":["Private Bill","Public Bill","Official Bill","Non-Official Bill"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"If the Bill introduced by the ruling party MP it is known as","choices":["Act","law","Private Bill","Public Bill"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"How many 'Readings' a Bill has to cross in each House to get passed?","choices":["Two","Four","Five","Three"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"If Legislature has only one House, it is know as","choices":["Mono-cameralism","Cameralism","Bi-cameralism","Uni-cameralism"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"What kind of majority does an Ordinary Bill require to pass in Parliament?","choices":["Special majority","Absolute majority","Simple majority","Overwhelming majority"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"What is the purpose of the Joint Session of the Parliament?","choices":["to pass the budget","to elect the speaker","to remove the president","to resolve the deadlock between the two houses"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Annual statement of income and expenditure of the Government is know as","choices":["Agenda","Catalogue","Calender","Budget"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Who will present the Budget in the month of March every in the Lok Sabha?","choices":["Finance Minister","Prime Minister","Home Minister","Speaker"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Can the Money Bill be rejected by the President when comes second time after reconsideration by the Lower House with or without modification","choices":["Yes","No, it has to be signed by the President","His will & wish","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Name the highest or apex court of India?","choices":["Federal Court","Lok-adalath","Supreme Court","International Court"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"How is the supremacy of the Constitution safeguarded?","choices":["by independent and impartial Judiciary","by the parliament","by the cabinet","press"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What is the total strength of the Supreme Court?","choices":["30","Twenty Five Judges and One Chief Justice together Twenty-Six","35","29"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Who does appoint the Judges of the Supreme Court?","choices":["Cabinet","President on his own","President appoints the Judges after consulting the Chief Justice of India","President by consulting Prime Minister"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Who does appoint Chief Justice of the Supreme Court?","choices":["By the President","By the Prime Minister","By the cabinet","By the Speaker of Lok Sabha"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Is the President bound to any one of the appointment of the Chief Justice of India?","choices":["Yes","Bound to the advice of the Parliament","None of these","No"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"What is the retirement age of the Chief Justice and Judges of the Supreme Court?","choices":["62 years","60 years","65 years","58 years"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Name the process through which Judges of the Supreme Court and High Court are removed?","choices":["No-confidence motion","By order of the Speaker","By order of the Prime Minister","Through impeachment Motion"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"On what grounds the Judges are removed?","choices":["Failed to give effective Judgment","Proved misbehavior, incapacity","Absconding from duty","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What is the present salary of the Chief Justice of India?","choices":["Rs. 1,33,000","Rs. 1,00,000/-","Rs. 1,35,000/-","Rs. 1,34,000/-"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What is the salary of the Supreme Court Judges of India?","choices":["Rs.90,000/-","Rs.1,22,000/-","Rs.1,26,000/-","Rs.1,30,000/-"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The jurisdiction exercised by the Supreme Court to deal the cases related to the powers of the Centre and States is known as","choices":["Appellate Jurisdiction","Original Jurisdiction","Advisory Jurisdiction","Special Jurisdiction"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Name the jurisdiction exercised by the Courts to deal the cases come from the subordinate courts?","choices":["Appellate Jurisdiction","Constitutional Jurisdiction","Original Jurisdiction","Judicial activism"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Under what jurisdiction, the cases involving the interpretation of the Constitution, are dealt by the Supreme Court?","choices":["Original Jurisdiction","Special Jurisdiction","Appellate Jurisdiction","Advisory Jurisdiction"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Name the Article, empowering the Supreme Court to issue writs for the enforcement of FRs?","choices":["Under Article 32","Under Article 33","Under Article 35","Under Article 40"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Name the jurisdiction exercised by the Supreme Court to give or not to give advices to the President whenever the later asked on the matter related to public issue?","choices":["Original Jurisdiction","Appellate Jurisdiction","Lok adalath","Advisory Jurisdiction"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Not obeying the judgment of the Supreme Court is know as","choices":["Insulting the Court","Disrespecting the Court","Contempt of Court","Dishonouring the Court"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The power of the Supreme Court to examine the Constitutional validity of the laws of the Central and State Governments is known as","choices":["Judicial Authority","Judicial Review","Judicial Activism","Judicial Remand"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Who can decide the election disputes of President and Vice-President of India?","choices":["High court","Parliament","Supreme Court","Executive"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Is the Supreme Court bound by its own judgment?","choices":["No","Yes","Bound to some extent","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What is required for the Supreme Court to deliver impartial judgments?","choices":["Independent constitution","Govt's interference","Free from political control","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2}],[{"question":"The Governor of a state is","choices":["Directly elected by the people","Elected by the state legislature","Appointed by the President","Appointed by the parliament"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The Governor Powers do not include","choices":["Legislative powers","Military powers","Pardoning powers","Emergency powers"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The Governor of a state is responsible for his actions to","choices":["The state legislative assembly","The president","The prime minister","The chief justice of the high court"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"State Governors are","choices":["Instruments of control of the centre over the state","Nominees of the chief minister","Elected by the Rajya sabha","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Ordinances issued by a state governor are subject to approval of","choices":["The president of India","Chief Minister of the state","Union parliament","State legislative concerned"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Who, among the following, is not appointed by the Governor","choices":["Chief Minister","High Court judges","Members of the State Public Service Commission","Advocate General"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Legislative council is","choices":["Dissolved after 6 years","Dissolved after 5 years","Dissolved after 3 years","Not dissolved"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"A High Court Judge retires at the age of","choices":["65","63","60","62"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Constitution empowers state governments to make special law for","choices":["Women and children","Workers working in the mines","Farmers","Unemployed youths"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"President rule is imposed in a state","choices":["When there is no clear majority","When state legislative passes a resolution to that effect","When there is difference of opinion between the Governor and the Chief Minister.","When the state government doesnt follow the direction given by the Prime Minister."],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"This is not the power of the chief minister","choices":["Formation of government","Control over minister","Chief advisor to the governor","Control over state judiciary"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"The minimum age for a person to be appointed as the governor of a state is","choices":["35","40","30","25"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"By convention, the Governor of a state generally belongs to","choices":["The same state","Some other state","The I.A.S. cadre","The same zone"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Who among the following holds office during the pleasure of the president?","choices":["Governor","Election Commissioner","Prime minister","Speaker of the loksabha"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The executive of the state government comprises the","choices":["President, Governor and the Chief Minister","Governor and the Chief Minister","Governor and the council of ministers","Chief Minister and his council of ministers"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Suffrage means","choices":["The right to suffer","The right of the citizen to expose the suffering of others","The right to vote","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Which of the following subjects may never be discussed in a state legislature","choices":["Conduct of a high court judge","Conduct of a marshal of the house","Items of the charged expenditure in the budget","Conduct of the Governor"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Who, among the following, can remove a chief minister from office?","choices":["State legislative assembly","Governor","President","Supreme court of India"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Election to a state legislature is conducted by the","choices":["State Governor","Chief Minister","Chief Secretary of the state","Election commission"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"When a state assembly is dissolved, the law making power for the state concerned rests with the","choices":["State Governor","Union Parliament","President of India","Chief Justice of India"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The Chief Minister remains in power as long as he enjoys the confidence of the","choices":["Prime minister","Governor","State legislative assembly","people of the state"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Members of the council of ministers are appointed by","choices":["Chief Minister","Governor","Governor on the advice of the chief minister","State legislative assembly"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"A joint sitting of the Vidhana  Sabha and vidhana parishat of a state is presided over by the","choices":["Governor of the state","Chief minister","Chairman of the vidhana parishad","Speaker of the vidhana sabha"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The authority to dissolve a state legislative assembly is vested in the","choices":["Chief minister of a state"," Speaker of the state assembly","President of India","State governor"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"A few members of the legislative council are nominated by the","choices":["Chief minister","Governor of the state","Chairman of the legislative council","President of India"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Total members in the Legislative Council should not be less than","choices":["250","80","20","40"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Governor will act as per the advice of the council of Ministers while","choices":["Giving assent to a bill","Dissolving the Legislative Assembly","Recommending Presidents Rule","Appointing the advocate General"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"The number of ministers, including the chief minister, in a state shall no be less than","choices":["15","12","10","5"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The number of ministers including the chief minister shall not exceed____ of the total number of M.L.A.s","choices":["25%","30%","15%","20%"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The Chief Minister of state is","choices":["Elected directly by the people","Selected by the President of India","Selected by hid party President","Elected by the Members of the Legislative Assembly"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"The Chief Minister is answerable for his acts of omission and commission to","choices":["The People","His party","Legislative Assembly","Investigation"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Budget of a State Government is based on","choices":["The vision of the council of Ministers","The preparation of the official of the state","The direction of the central Government","The direction of World Trade Organization"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The position of the chief minister in council of ministers is","choices":["the first among equal","the supreme commander","the virtual dictator","no difference at all with regard to position & status"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"To become a judge of the High Court one must be a practicing advocate of the High Court for at least","choices":["years","10 years","15 years","5 years"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The judges of a High Court are","choices":["Liable to be transferred","Not liable to be transferred","Liable to be transferred once in 2 years","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The Chief Justice of a High Court gets a salary of","choices":["Rs. 56,000","Rs. 90,000","Rs. 75,000","Rs. 80,000"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"High Courts have original jurisdiction in","choices":["Admirality","Civil matters","Criminal matters","Matters not related will or divorce"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"High courts have appellate jurisdiction in","choices":["Civil matters","Criminal matters","Both criminal and civil matters","Constitutional matters"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The decision of a High Court over rules the decision of","choices":["all other lower courts","is not binding on all other lower courts","it just a matter of reference to lower courts","none of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Public interest litigation can be entertained by a High court whenever","choices":["the public is irresponsible","the public neglect the Governments interests","the public interest is undermined","the public interest becomes personal interest of the high court"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The high court has","choices":["The power of superintendence over all other lower courts","The power to create lower courts","The power to disengage the business of a lower court","The power to dissolve all or any lower court"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Judicial activism is","choices":["for the protection of the Rights of the citizens","for curtailment of the power of the Government","for the curtailment of active organization","for the follow up of the courts directions"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The independence of judiciary is necessary","choices":["effectively act as a guardian of peoples rights","to curb the powers of the Executive","to discipline the behaviour of the legislature","to encourage the media to counter the wrong decisions of the government"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The Judiciary is","choices":["A part of the Government","Nothing to do with the Government","Independent of Government","Against the Government"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The judiciary is provided by","choices":["The Constitution","The people","The Government","United Nations Organisation"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The best test of excellence of Government is the efficiency of its executive","choices":["The efficiency of its executive","The efficiency of its legislative","The efficiency of its Judicial system","All of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The Judges of the High Court are","choices":["Appointed by the Chief Minister","Appointed by the Speaker of the Vidhana Sabha","Appointed by the President of India","Appointed by the Governor"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Judicial Review means","choices":["Reviewing the laws passed by the legislature","Examining the actions of the Executive","Scrutinizing the lower courts order","Supervising the implementation of the D.P.S.P"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The Supreme Court has the Power to","choices":["Create High Courts","Create the Whole Judicial system","Supervise and control the High Court","None of these"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"To become a chief minister of a state one must have attained the age of","choices":["25 years","30 years","35 years","40 years"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The list of SCs & STs is drawn by","choices":["Governor","President","Prime Minister","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"There can be reservation of seats in Lok Sabha & State Legislative Assemblies for SCs amd STs is contained in","choices":["Article 352, 360","Article 356, 359","Article 330, 332","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Article 243 (D) & 243 (T) provides for reservation of seats for SCs and STS in","choices":["Lok Sabha","Rajya Sabha","Panchayat Raj","Vidhana Sabha"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Under Article 338____ can be established for the SCs and STs","choices":["National Commission","Human Rights courts","Civil Courts","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"National Commission for SCs & STs shall have all the power of a","choices":["High Court","Supreme Court","Civil Court","Criminal Court"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Special Provisions for Scs and Sts are also contained in","choices":["Part I & II of the constitution","Part III & IV of the constitution","Part X of the constitution","Part of XVI of the constitution"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"___ Provides for grants-in-aid to the state for promoting the welfare of the SCs & STs","choices":["Article 280","Article 275","Article 249","Article 300"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The legally permissible age for marriage of a boy & girl is","choices":["21 & 18 years","16 & 18 years","25 & 23 years","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Practices derogatory to use status of women in renounced under","choices":["Article 51 A (e)","Article 32","Article 50","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Right to education has been guaranteed to children between the age of","choices":["6-14 years","7-12 years","8-10 years","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The term backward class implies backwardness","choices":["Socially & educationally","Economically","Culturally","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Backward classes commission is appointed by the","choices":["Prime Minister","President","Governor","Chief Minister of all states"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Types of emergencies provided in the Indian Constitution is","choices":["4","5","6","3"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"The power to declare emergency is vested in the","choices":["Prime Minister","President","Governor","Chief Minister"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"National Emergency may be declared on the ground of","choices":["Internal disturbance","Political instability","War","Natural calamities"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"National Emergency may be declared on ____grounds","choices":["5","2","6","3"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"National Emergency may be declared under the following Article","choices":["360","2","352","375"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"National emergency can be declared when the cabinet communicates to the president","choices":["Orally","In writing","Either orally or in writing","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Proclamation of emergency must be laid before","choices":["Both the Houses of the Parliament","Either House of the Parliament","Before the supreme court","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Proclamation of emergency must be approved within","choices":["2 months","1 Month","6 Months","1 year"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"A resolution approving the proclamation must be passed by","choices":["Simple majority","Special Majority","Either special or simple majority","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Once approved, proclamation of emergency remains in force for","choices":["1 Year","6 Years","6 months","3 months"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Proclamation of emergency may be varied or cancelled by the","choices":["Lok sabha","Rajya Sabha","Supreme Court","President"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Proclamation of emergency at the first instance remains in force for","choices":["6 months","1 month","3 months","2 months"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"During Emergency the states can be given directions by the","choices":["Supreme Court","Centre","Parliament","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"During emergency, there is automatic suspension of rights guaranteed under","choices":["Article 14","Article 21","Article 19","Article 18"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"President can suspend the enforcement of fundamental Rights except","choices":["Articl2 14 & 19","Article 18 & 20","Article 21 & 22","Article 20 & 21"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"So far National Emergency has been declared____ times in India","choices":["Five","Six","Three","One"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"State emergency is also called as","choices":["Presidents rule","Prime Minister Rule","Governors Rule","Chief Justice Rule"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"State Emergency can be declared when there is","choices":["War","Failure of Constitutional machinery in states","Financial Crisis","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"President can impose State emergency when he receives a report from the","choices":["Chief Minister","Governor","Chief Justice","Attorney General"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"During State Emergency the President exercises the power of the","choices":["Chief Minister","Prime Minister","Governor","Chief Justice"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Financial Emergency may be declared when there is ________","choices":["Financial instability","War","Internal disturbance","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The duration of financial emergency is _______","choices":["6 months","2 months","3 months","1 year"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Federal constitutions means a constitution in which powers are divided between the___","choices":["Central & state","States only","People & States","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The new ground of emergency added in 1978 to Article 352 was____","choices":["War","External Aggression","Armed Rebellion","Internal Disturbance"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The powers to superintendent, direct & control elections is vested in the______","choices":["Planning commission","Finance Commission","Election Commission","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Election commission is _____ member commission","choices":["Single","Double","Multi","Four"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The conditions of services of the election commissioners may be determined by the___","choices":["Prime Minister","Governor","President","Chief Justice of India"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The removal of Chief Election Commissioner may be on grounds similar to that of ____","choices":["Judge of a High Court","Judge of the Supreme Court","Attorney General of India","Governor of a State"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Election Commissioners are appointed by the____","choices":["Chief Justice of India","Prime Minister","President","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Every citizen of the age of ____ years is eligible to vote in an election","choices":["21 years","16years","25 years","18 years"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"No. of rolls in a territorial constituency shall be ___","choices":["Two","One","Three","Unlimited"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Seats are reserved in favour of ___","choices":["SC & ST","Aged persons","Sick persons","Disabled persons"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"No. of seats to be reserved for Anglo Indian community in Lok Sabha is ___","choices":["Three","Two","One","Unlimited"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"The term of office of Election Commissioner is ___","choices":["1 Year","2 years","5 years","6 years"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"The members of the Anglo Indian community are nominated by the ____","choices":["Chief Minister","Prime Minister","President","Chief Justice of India"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"___ no. of days are allowed to file nomination","choices":["7 days","8 days","30 days","15 days"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"No. of days allowed to withdraw nomination papers is ___","choices":["1 day","3 days","2 days","15 days"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"No. of days allowed for campaigning","choices":["10 days","30 days","15 days","20 days"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Election disputes can be adjudicated only by____","choices":["High Court","Criminal Court","Election Commission","Civil Court"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Constitutions are classified into ____","choices":["Rigid","flexible","Rigid & flexible","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The method of amending rigid constitution is by ___","choices":["Simple majority","Special majority","Cannot be amended","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Procedure to amend the constitution is contained in____","choices":["Article 268","Article 368","Article 338","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"No. of methods of amending the constitution ____","choices":["Two","One","Three","Four"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Consent by states for amending the constitution is known as ____","choices":["Resignation","Ratification","Registration","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"42nd Amendment Act came into force in","choices":["1956","1960","1976","1978"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"The words added to the preamble by 42nd amendment were","choices":["Socialist only","Secular only","Integrity only","All of these"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Which among the following were given supremacy over fundamental rights.","choices":["Fundamental duties","Citizenship","DPSP","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Life of Lokha Sabha was increased from 5 to ___ years","choices":["6 years","7 years","9 years","10 years"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"44th Constitutional Amendment Act came into force in ___","choices":["1972","1976","1978","1980"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"____ was restored to 5 years","choices":["Life of Rajya Sabha","Life of Lok Sabha","Life of Both","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"73rd Amendment Act 1993 recognised the importance of____","choices":["Water Commission","Local Self Govt.","Central Govt.","State Govt."],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Establishment of ____ was the subject matter of 74th Amendment Act.","choices":["Corporations","Municipalities","High Court","None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Reservation in promotion to SC �s & STs is permitted _____","choices":["Article 16","Article 15 (4)","Article 16 (4-A)","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Article 21 (A) was a gift of ____ Amendment Act.","choices":["81st","82nd ","86th ","89th "],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Right to education under Article 21 (A) is now a ____","choices":["Legal right","Constitutional Right","Fundamental Right","None of these"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"91st Amendment Act 2003 strengthens_____","choices":["Anti-defection Law","Preventive Detection Law","Ordinary property Law","None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The total no. of council of ministers including the Prime Minister should not exceed ____","choices":["10%","20%","15%","30%"],"correctAnswer":2}],[{"question":"Is  it  possible  to  separate  professional  ethics  from  personal  ethics","choices":[" no"," yes"," possible to some extent"," none of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Do you agree that Personal Ethics is the foundation of Professional Ethics","choices":[" yes to some extent"," Yes and No"," No"," Yes"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"What does the Professional Ethics deal","choices":[" It deals with the ethical standards accepted by the professional community"," It deals with the legal standards"," It deals with the business aspects"," It deals with official matters"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What standards on which the Engineer have to comply with","choices":[" Legal"," Commerce"," The standards according to model rules of professional Conduct provided by various agencies , to the public , to the clients, to the employers and the customers","Ethical"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Expand the abbreviated word �NSPE�","choices":["National Scheme for professional Ethics"," National society for professional Engineers"," National sector~wise programme efficiency"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What are the codes provided by NSPE to apply in particular circumstances","choices":[" to avoid conflict of interest","  to understand the problem of engineers"," to protect wealth"," to inspect the agenda"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The following are the aims of the professional Ethics","choices":[" developing analytical  standards"," toleration on agreement and ambiguity"," sense of developing ethical principles"," recognition of ethical issues"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Are Engineers morally responsible for causing harm intentionally, negligently, or recklessly","choices":[" No"," Yes "," Yes to some extent"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What is one of  the three basic attitudes towards the responsibilities of Engineer","choices":[" minimalist","  uncritical acceptance of authority"," inspection"," none of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The responsibility of engineers are divided into ","choices":[" Four"," Three"," Two"," Five"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"What do you mean by �minimalist approach�","choices":["Sticking on maximum acceptable standards"," Sticking on to minimum acceptable standards"," Sticking on full acceptable standards"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"What is emphasized in reasonable/considerable care","choices":[" Attention to those who are at risk of being harmed and to prevent the progress or adverse effect of harm"," Attention to those who are not at risk"," Attention on both of the above"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Is considerable care beyond the minimalist approach","choices":[" No"," Yes"," No to some extent"," Yes to extent"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"In �Good Work Views�, focus is given on","choices":[" Concept of skilful work"," Concept of legal work"," Concept of logical work"," The concept of responsibility beyond the legal and moral duty"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Is �Self �Interest� impediment or hindrance to responsibilty ","choices":["No"," Yes"," Yes to some extent"," None of these"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Is �Fear� impediment or hindrance to responsibility ","choices":[" No"," yes to some extent"," Yes & No"," Yes"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"What is the other hindrance to the responsibility ","choices":[" self deception"," Self assessment"," Self realization"," Negligence"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Honesty is____________ ","choices":[" perfectness"," Readiness"," truthfulness","surrendering to God"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Dharma is__________ ","choices":[" Sincerity"," Castle belief"," What is good for the self","Truth of justice"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Honesty is __________ ","choices":[" Not liked by all"," Liked by all but not practiced"," liked in others"," liked by one and all"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Engineering honesty is doing ___________ ","choices":["What is right for oneself"," What is good for the society"," What is good for the employer"," What earns money quickly"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Engineers should not indulge in__________ ","choices":[" Fraudulent business "," constructive measures"," Healthy attitudes to words society"," None of above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Telling the truth when should not is ____________ ","choices":[" Honesty"," Dharma of an engineer"," Misusing the truth"," Business principle"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Misusing the truth is_______ ","choices":[" Disclosing the information when should not"," Sincerity in engineering"," Doing good service to the customer"," Upholding the dignity of the profession"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Failure to reveal the truth means__________ ","choices":[" Lying"," Protecting the employer in interest"," Protecting the company interest"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Deliberate deception means_____________ ","choices":[" An engineer is deliberately deceiving the customer"," An engineer is deceiving the employer"," An engineer is doing service to the society"," An engineer is doing good service to both employer and society"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Withholding information is ____________ ","choices":[" Omitting necessary information to customer"," Omitting necessary information to the employer"," Committing an offence"," committing an error of judgement"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Corrupting the truth means __________ ","choices":[" Conflicts of interest"," Conflicts of judgement"," Conflicts of service"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Integrity in engineering means____________ ","choices":[" Quality of being honest and fair"," Quality of service to the employer"," Quality of self~esteemed behaviour"," Quality of self~aggrandizement"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Integrity means ____________ ","choices":[" Not settling for less than what you deserve"," Not giving out anything at all"," Not yielding to public pressure"," Not sacrificing in approach and appearance"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Trimming in engineering means ____________ ","choices":[" Dressing the bushes"," Dressing hair"," Smoothing the irregularities to your convenience"," Smartness in approach and appearance"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Cooking in engineering means __________ ","choices":[" Cook the food"," Cook a story"," Retain only what you want","Leave out what others need"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Forging in engineering means ___________ ","choices":[" Shaping the metal"," Make a fraudulent copy"," Inventing some research data"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":"Plagiarism means ____________ ","choices":[" Use of intellectual property of others "," Copying wanted information from different sources"," Research work"," Knitting a theory to suit your arguments"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Trade secret doesn�t include _________ ","choices":[" Formulas"," Patterns"," Devices"," Colours"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Patent right is for _______ ","choices":[" 10 years"," 20 years"," 40 years"," 100 years"],"correctAnswer":1},{"question":"Trademarks  doesn�t include ____________ ","choices":[" Designs"," Sounds"," Phrases"," Fair"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Copyright is for _____________ ","choices":[" 50 years after his or her death"," 15 years after his or her death"," 100 years after his or her death"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineer is not supposed to reveal any information to his client _____________ ","choices":[" In the interest of his client","In employer�s interest"," In the interest of the society"," None of the above"],"correctAnswer":3},{"question":"Reliability in engineering means ____________ ","choices":[" Probability of a product or a system"," Quality of the person who sells the product"," Quality of the company which produces the product"," Probable use or misuse of a product"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Risk in engineering means __________ ","choices":[" Taking risk to venture out something "," Without taking risk nothing can be achieved"," The potential that something unwanted may occur"," An inadvertent oversight"],"correctAnswer":2},{"question":" Liability means ____________ ","choices":["  Whenever an act harms others it must be compensated","  Compensation not obligatory","  When a customer buys a service or product liability ceases","  None of the above"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Risk as a maximizing benefit is understood by","choices":[" Risk /benefit analysis"," Straight �line benefit"," Cost/benefit analysis"," Break-analysis"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Conflicts of interest exists when an improper judgement is made by professional may not be due to","choices":["Protecting the public health","Temptations","Loyalties","Influences"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"It is not a kind of trademark","choices":["Goodwill","Symbols","Sounds","Designs"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Conflict of interest may be","choices":["Potential","False","Created","Imaginary"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Revealing confidential information means","choices":["Misusing the truth","Breach of contract","Criminal breach of trust","Violation of patent right"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The professional ethics deals with ________accepted by the professional group community","choices":["Ethical standards","Scientific standards","Moral standards","Social standards"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The obligation and prerogatives associated with a special role is referred to as","choices":["Role morality ","Duty","Responsibility"," Ethics"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The codes of ethics can be taken as guidelines by the engineers to","choices":["Resolve the conflicts","Formulate the problem","Overcome the work pressure ","Escape the responsibility"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"No code will give _____ to get solutions for ethical problems","choices":["An algorithm","Guidelines","Set of ideas","Ethical standards"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not taken as aim of engineer?","choices":["Shifting of responsibilities","Recognition of ethical issues","Moral imagination","Sense of responsibility"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Responsibility is assigned as belonging to persons in","choices":["Both (b) and (c) ","Rule","Morality","Obligation"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Recklessly causing harm is","choices":["Not with an intention to cause harm but acting in conscious awareness that harm is likely to take place","Unknowingly causing harm but failing to take due care ","Purposely causing harm","Both (a) and (b)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following doesn�t depict the attitude towards responsibility?","choices":["Protest","Good works","Reasonable care","Minimalist"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"In reasonable care concept of responsibility, the attention paid is to","choices":["Those who are at risk of being harmed","The employee","To client","Self"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineer tempted by their own interest to act in contrary to interest of others","choices":["Self~interest","Self~deception","Ignorance","Egoism"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Ignorance as a hurdle to responsibility is not due to","choices":["Fear","Over confidence","Lack of imagination"," pressure and deadlines"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The tendency of interpreting situations according to their views and imposing the views is","choices":["Egocentric","Self interest","Confined vision ","Both (b) and(c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineer COE emphasize that the engineer should have_____ in discharging their duties","choices":["Autonomy","Fidelity to employers","Obligation to public","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"________is not the symptom of group thinking","choices":["Egocentric tendency ","Mind guarding","Illusion of unanimity","Self~censorship"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Tendency of shifting responsibility will come down if there is","choices":["Group thinking","Microscopic vision","Fear","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not advised by the NSPE code to engineer?","choices":["Not to avoid deceptive acts","Not to use firms name in dishonest business","To have professional obligations","To be honest"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following qualities an responsible engineer should not have regard to risk?","choices":["Dishonest in assessing","Be aware of different approaches to the determination and risk","Not be deceiving","Aware of difficulty"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The owner of �Patent right� retains his patent right for ___________ years (OR)patent holder does not allow others to use patented information for ___________ years from date of filling","choices":["20","50","75","100"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The principle obligations of engineer is to safe guard the public by ","choices":["Spreading the information before the disaster occurs","Finding out the truth","Withholding the information","Deliberate deception"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the characteristics of high risk technologies susceptible to accident is complex","choices":["Combination ","working of system","Interaction","Designs"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the ways of reducing risk is","choices":["Tight coupling ","Complex interactions","Normalization of deviance","Changing the working systems"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"�Minimalist view� means","choices":["A concept of responsibility","A narrow thinking ","A ministerial view","A novel plan to minimize industrial loss"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Basic attitude towards responsibility is","choices":["Minimalist","Recklessly causing harm","Negligently causing harm","Intentionally causing harm"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"They are not trade secrets ","choices":["Principles","Patterns","Formulas","Devices"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not a trade secret?","choices":["Theorem","Equipment","Formulae","Pattern"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Formula of a soft drink is an example of","choices":["Trade secret","Patent","Copy right","Trade mark"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Copyright protects the expression of ideas but not the","choices":["Ideas themselves","Deriving ideas","Predicting ideas","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"A company cannot have claim if the knowledge used is","choices":["Generic information","Stolen from the company","Used to create the same product","Both (b) and (C)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not conflict of interest as applied to making judgement?","choices":["Virtual","Apparent","Potential","Actual"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"A fault tree is used to","choices":["Assess the risk involved","Claim compensation","Take free consent","Improve safety"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Risk estimation can be done by using","choices":["Event tree","Trimming","Cooking","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The use of intellectual property of others without their permission or credit is referred as","choices":["Plagiarism","Trimming","Cooking","Forging"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not preserved as an intellectual property?","choices":["Government regulations","Copyrights","Patents","Trade secrets"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Acceptable risk means ","choices":["Risk of harm equal to probability of producing benefits","Risk which is the natural part of the process","Inevitable risk","Risk which cannot be avoided"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Allowing increased number of deviances from prescribed standards of safety and acceptable risk is referred to as","choices":["Normalizing deviance","Identification of risk","Estimation of risk","Probable risk"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Lay public estimation of likely hood of low probability risks associated with the causes of life is generally","choices":["Over estimation","Under estimation","Actual estimation","Rough estimation"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"In which of the following the competent technical knowledge of engineers is not required for certification in cases involving?","choices":["Legal matters","Effective goods","Accidents","Patent violation"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Expert testimony doesn�t demand ","choices":["Adequate time for thorough investigation","Consulting extensively with lawyer","Expert legal knowledge","Objective and unbiased demeanour"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"In issuing testimony which of the following is not desired by an expert","choices":["Not to maintain an objective and be biased","Be open to information, even during the course of trial","Not to accept, if he cannot do so with good conscience","Not to accept, if there is no adequate time"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Which of the following is not the concept of responsibility?","choices":["Utilitarian","Minimalist","Reasonable care","Good works"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"For an ethical engineer responsibility is","choices":["Both legal and moral","Moral responsibility","Legal responsibility","Social responsibility"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One�s wish of being an ethical engineer ","choices":["His wish of being an ethical person","His family members wish of him being an ethical person","His employers wish of him being an ethical person","All of these"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"What is morally wrong?","choices":["Cannot be measured as constitutional right","Can be measured as constitutional right","Can be legally right","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"A professional engineer take the help of COE specifically when he enters into","choices":["Ethical crisis","Doubts","Confusion","Legal complications"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"The �risk experts� approach usually","choices":["Utilitarian","Biased","Favourable to employer","None"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"This is not the aim of studying Engineering Ethics","choices":["Addressing un clarity","Analyzing concepts","Engaging sense of responsibility","Procuring faultless results"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineers shall issue public statements only","choices":["On the personal responsibility","Based on the reports sent by higher officers","In objective manner","In subjective manner"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"An engineer may not be held legally liable for causing harm, when the harm is caused","choices":["Internationally","Ignorantly","nNegligently","Recklessly"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the characteristics of Profession is","choices":["It gives scope to exercise one�s skill","It gives monopoly on service","It provides opportunity to help the poor and needy","It demands high standards of honesty"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the views on the responsibility of engineers is","choices":["They are absolutely reliable","They should do good works","They should take reasonable responsibility","They are strictly liable"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the most impediments to responsibility is","choices":["Self deception","Rampant corruption at higher level","Interference by higher officer","Interference by politicians"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"This is not impediment to responsibility","choices":["Self respect","Ignorance","Self deception","Fear"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Conflict of interest exists for an engineer when he is subjected to","choices":["Loyalties","Professional impediments","Professional harassments","Threat"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Professional autonomy means ","choices":["Exercising independent and objective judgements ","Liberty to express independent view","Liberty in selecting the work","Independent body controlling profession"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"It doesn�t amount to misusing the truth","choices":["Biased professional information","Failure to seek out the truth","Withholding information","Deliberation deception"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the ways of misusing the truth is ","choices":["Failure to seek the truth","Exaggerating the truth","Making the confused statement","Making totally false statement"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Good work means","choices":["Work above and beyond the call of duty","Responsible work","Work involving high risk","Superior work done with great care and skill"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Cooking means","choices":["Retaining results which fit the theory","Making deceptive statements","Boiling under pressure","Misleading the public about the quality of product"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Forging means","choices":["Inventing research data which are reported","Mixing material under high pressure","Signing in the name of other person","Strengthening material by special process"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"An example for forging is","choices":["Mentioning of experiments to obtain data which were never conducted","Obtaining data by conducting an experiment","Referring to all research data","Both (a) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Egocentric tendency means","choices":["Interpreting situation from limited view","Superiority complex","Arrogant and irresponsible behaviour","Habit of condemning view of others"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Group thinking","choices":["Is an impediment for responsibility","Leads to confusion and may cause loss","Is an impediment in the progress of work","Is useful to understand different facts of the problem"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Tight couple means","choices":["Binding two beams tightly","Erecting two pillars side by side","Process tightly coupled","Strong adhesive material"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One process or function of one component that affect the other and spread the adverse effect to the entire system is observed in","choices":["Tight coupled","Loosely coupled","Complexly interactive","None"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"In ___________ systems, risk estimation is difficult","choices":["Complexly interactive","Tightly coupled ","Loosely coupled","Both (b) and (C)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"A compound measure of probability and magnitude of adverse effect is known as","choices":["Risk","Benefit","Compensation","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Lying is ","choices":["Intentionally conveying false or misleading information","Deception","Falsehood","Both (b) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Trimming is ","choices":["Smoothing of irregularities to make the data to appear accurate and precise","Retaining the entire data","Consolidating the data","Both (a) and (c)"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineering ethics is a ","choices":["Preventive ethics","Developing ethics","Natural ethics","Scientifically developed ethics"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineering ethics ","choices":["Stimulates moral imagination","Provides accurate knowledge in the field of engineering","Stimulates to conduct research","Stresses on time management"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Professional ethics is","choices":["Set of rules related to personal character of professional","Traditional rules observed since a long time","Set of rules passed by professional bodies","Set of standards adopted by professionals"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Professional ethics takes into account of ","choices":["Personnel character of engineers","Temperament of engineers","Religious bent of mind of engineers","Social background of engineers"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"Engineering profession is considered to be like a building its foundation is","choices":["Honesty","Hard and sincere work ","Expert engineering knowledge and skill","Sound common sense and expert knowledge"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the aims in studying engineering ethics is to ","choices":["Gain better in site into the profession","Know the secrets of profession ","Develop analytical skill ","Understand the professional problems"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"One of the aims of engineering ethics is to","choices":["Stimulate the moral imagination","Inspire engineers to acquire in depth knowledge in their field","Acquire new skills in engineering, testing and research","Make engineers self confident in discharging their duties"],"correctAnswer":0},{"question":"This is not the aim of studying engineering ethics ","choices":["Crimping","Cooking","Forging","Plagiarism"],"correctAnswer":0}]]